You can't believe everything you see.
Body Double is a crime, mystery, thriller film directed by Brian De Palma.
After losing an acting role and his girlfriend, Jake Scully finally catches a
break: he gets offered a gig house-sitting in the Hollywood Hills.
While peering through the beautiful home's telescope one night,
he spies a gorgeous woman dancing in her window.
But when he witnesses the girl's murder, it leads Scully through the netherworld of the adult
entertainment industry on a search for answers—with porn actress Holly Body as his guide.
Jake Scully, played by Craig Wasson.
Holly Body, played by Melanie Griffith.
Sam Bouchard, played by Gregg Henry.
Gloria Revelle, played by Deborah Shelton.
Det. Jim McLean, played by Guy Boyd.
Rubin, played by Dennis Franz.
Body Double is a 1984 American neo-noir erotic thriller film
directed, co-written, and produced by Brian De Palma.
It stars Craig Wasson, Gregg Henry, Melanie Griffith, and Deborah Shelton.
The film is a direct homage to the 1950s films of Alfred Hitchcock, specifically Rear Window, Vertigo, and Dial M for
Murder, taking plot lines and themes (such as voyeurism, panic attack and obsession) from the first two.
At the time of its release, the film was a commercial failure, earning $8.8 million at the box office against a production budget of $10 million, as well as mixed
reviews, though Griffith's performance earned praise and earned her a nomination for the Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting Actress – Motion Picture.
Subsequently, the film received positive appraisal from cinema
fans and is now considered to be a cult film.
The film explores themes of police,
claustrophobia, witness, film in film, murder.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.